marapets.com 2019-06-14

# MaraPets - Contact Us

**MaraPets Ltd** operates:  
_www.marapets.com_   
&  
_www.marasites.com_  
this Privacy Policy applies to both  |   
---|---  
  
Our Privacy Policy describes what information our sites collect from users who sign up and play our FREE game. MaraPets Ltd is a UK based company with our data stored on our secure servers in Canada. Our policy is European Union GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) compliant and practices are guided by the United States' Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) of 1998.    
Data We Collect: |    
We only collect the minimum amount of necessary data we require for your registered account to be able to play and use our sites properly. The data stored for each registered account is IP Address, Email Address, cookie ID and browser/device information. If you link your account with Facebook, Google or Microsoft for faster login/registration, we do not store any additional information - it is simply matched to any email address we already store for you. _We do not collect ANY personally identifiable information_  
---|---  
  
How We Store Data: |    
We take your privacy and our sites security seriously. All data is stored on our secured systems, currently located in Canada. While we take all reasonable steps to protect your data, in the unlikely event our data is breached, we will notify all users of the site on our News and/or by email.   
  
How We Use Data: |    
All data we collect is only used to protect your registered account on our sites and to enhance your experience. The data is used to help us keep the sites safe for all users, to respond to a user's query or to notify you of any events or promotions we may have. You can unsubscribe to any emails from us at any time.   
  
Data We Share: |    
We only share data in exceptional circumstances when we are required to do so by law. We will never share or sell data we have collected.   
  
Third Party Data Collection: |    
MaraPets Ltd generates income from third party advertising and sales through PayPal. These companies have their own Privacy Policy and may collect their own data. We encourage you to review their policies.   
  
Remove My Data: |    
You can contact our Data Protection Officer at any time by email at **_marapets@gmail.com_** for a copy of the data we store on your account and to request your data is removed. 

Please note that we only store the minimum amount of data we require for you to have a FREE account on our sites. Any request for your data to be permanently removed from our systems will require the permanent removal of your account with us.   
  
Cookie Policy

We use cookies to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners. We also use cookies to store your account details, to keep you logged in and able to play Marapets. Marapets also uses Google services for analytics and advertising. By visiting our website, you are agreeing to [**how Google uses your data and cookies**](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/). 

Privacy Policy

To ensure this website is a safe and fun place for all we ensure that all online information is secure at all times. The site has a large number of online child players and therefore we take care to make sure that the content of the site is always safe for them. Any information gathered from you through this website will never be disclosed to any third party. This is includes Marapets staff, as all personal information is kept hidden from staff. 

Children under the age of 13 do not disclose any personal information about themselves. Just simply a username, email address, password and their gender, so that they can be uniquely identified in the game of Marapets. These are only used for them to keep their account on the site secure. ALL information can be removed as requested at any time, simply open a Support Ticket via the Contact Us link at the bottom of every page, and a staff member will do so. 

Marapets asks users 13 years and older to provide a valid first (and optional last name), valid e-mail address, birth date, gender, and country of location. All users can change or remove their information upon registration. 

Children under 13 can only have their accounts changed to an over 13 account upon the request of their parents, informing us that they have permission to do so. In such a case, the parents need to print out a Parental Consent form ( **click here**) and fill it in. They can then scan it and email to marapets@gmail.com or fax it (fax number coming soon). 

All information we collect and store is for gaming purposes only. Personal information of those 13 and over are, your email address for you to recover your password, your gender to identify you at the forums, date of birth to track which age groups use the site, your ip address to stop cheating with multiple accounts. 

For those who have verified their account via email as an over 13 year old account, have full access to the site and its features. Marasites, MaraMail and MaraJournals are free services. Any content you submit is optional and voluntary. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. Any files uploaded, websites or journals created on the Marasites or MaraPets system are by nature of being hosted, for the public and are thus publicly accessible. MaraMail is a free beta emailing service from Marapets which is to be used for chat only. Although all data from emails is encrypted from public and staff viewing, we will not take any responsibility for any loss via use of our email service. We therefore request that you do not use it for any online services which require personal information to be disclosed and espeically not for any site that could result in a loss of money or belongings - such as for Paypal, Ebay, Amazon, etc. MaraMail stores, processes and maintains your messages, contact lists and other data related to your account in order to provide the service to you. 

Participation in the Marapets Website is not based upon information collected. 

We have a strict policy against spyware and adware and popup advertisements. All of our advertising will be suitable for all ages, using third-party advertising companies. 

When visitors enter the site and members sign up to the site information such as computer operating system, IP address and web browser. This is only for research purposes to ensure that the site works its best with all users. If you would like your account or information removed, simply open a Support Ticket via the Contact Us link at the bottom of every page, and a staff member will do so. 

With respect to security, our server's physical location maintains a team of on-site security staff 24 hours per day, seven days per week. The security staff works with integrated closed circuit television and card access systems which are monitored from the security post in the main lobby. Staff have very limit access to the site. Only the site operator has full access. All of these are in place to ensure that there is no loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site. 

Finally, the site requires 'Session' Cookies to ensure that the game works. These are small text files that are stored on your computer. They keep you logged onto the site by telling our server who you are and what page of the site you last view. It also helps us to determine how many users and guests are online. These cookies can be easily removed using the appropriate options on your web browser. 

We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

As a parent of a player under 13 or as a member you can contact us at anytime, requesting to view all information we have stored, and you have the ability to review and control it at all times. 

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Marapets.com and Marasites.com. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [**click here**](https://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy please contact us at one of the following: Email marapets@gmail.com
